# JASON DONG

Dayton, OH  $\cdot$  jasondong7777@gmail.com  $\cdot$  thejasondong.com  $\cdot$  (937)-432-7340

### ABOUT

I am a Senior at Duke University pursuing a double major in Electrical and Computer Engineering and Computer Science, and a minor in History. I enjoy working with both hardware and software, and seeing how the intersection of both drive the world around us. Based on a reliable use of common sense and experience in leadership and research positions, I am prepared to lead a team or work in a team environment in various job positions while continuing to expand my own knowledge base.

## EDUCATION

**Duke University** 

Durham, NC

BSE - Electrical and Computer Engineering, BS - Computer Science, Minor - History

[AUG 2018 - MAY 2022 (EXP)]

Carroll High School

Dayton, OH

 $\operatorname{GED}$ 

GPA: 4.58 WGPA

[AUG 2014 - MAY 2018]

## WORK EXPERIENCE

**Duke University** 

Durham, NC

Teaching Assistant - EGR103, ECE350

[JAN 2021 - PRESENT, JAN 2020 - MAY 2020]

- (SPRING/FALL 2021) TA for ECE 350: Digital Systems, a class focusing on the design and implementation of digital logic, memory elements, FSMs, etc. Assisted students with designing and improving a Verilog based multi-cycle pipelined processor and deployment on final design projects onto a FPGA. I grade HW, exams, projects, and hold weekly office hours.
- (SPRING 2020) TA for Engineering 103: Computational Methods in Engineering, an introductory coding class in Python and using computational methods. Graded weekly lab reports, exams, weekly office hours, and served as a weekly lab TA.

# Air Force Life Cycle Management Center/EZAS

Dayton, OH

Hardware Electrical Engineering Intern

[MAY 2021 - AUG 2021, JUN 2020 - AUG 2020]

- (MAY 2021 AUG 2021) Designed and built payload for an UAV to have greater ADS-B range extension to track aircraft. Work included implementing scripts on Raspberry Pi for data acquisition, post processing with Python, electrical wiring, load analysis, housing design, and system modelling with Cameo.
- (JUN 2020 AUG 2020) Designed and developed an Arduino-based solar tracking device to recharge batteries to support remote operation of existing projects. I worked with designing the housing unit, electrical and mechanical components, and Arduino code.
- (MAY 2021 PRESENT) SECRET security clearance

Air Force Research Laboratory - Materials and Manufacturing Directorate Dayton, OH Engineering Intern [MAY 2019 - AUG 2019]

- Researched and documented in a final report proposal of current drone technology to recommend
  to the Air Force about system hardware, methodology, and other technologies to invest in for an
  automated aircraft damage inspection drone to scan military aircraft for damages due to normal
  operations, scratching, and corrosion.
- Experience working in AFRL's Materials Test & Evaluation lab helping with projects relevant to the Air Force Mission.

Air Force Research Laboratory - 711th Human Performance WingDayton, OHWright Scholar Intern|MAY 2017 - AUG 2017| - |MAY 2018 - AUG 2018|

- Worked in areas of Microbiology and Synthetic biology as a research assistant under Dr. Mike Goodson. Gained experience with various lab protocols and DNA analysis techniques.
- Participated as part of the USAF-Carroll iGEM Team, presenting at the biggest yearly synthetic biology convention (2017, 2018) on our work and publishing a final paper in PLOS.
- Worked on website creation, and HTML and CSS coding to display research results on our website.

### SKILLS

Programming Languages: Working Proficiency - Java, Python, Verilog, MIPS x86, Git, HTML/CSS

Familiar With - C, C++, SQL, Swift & iOS Development

3D Printing: CAD Design, Maintaining and operating 3D Printers Languages: Mandarin Chinese - Fluent in speech and comprehension

Spanish - Limited speaking

Video Production: Experience with iMovie, thumbnail editing, banner and logo design

# Relevant Coursework

**ECE:** Computer Architecture, Signals & Systems, Fields & Waves, Microelectronics, Magnetism & Optics, EGR Design & Communication, Digital Systems, Ocean Engineering, Graduate Image & Video Processing

CS: Data Structures & Algorithms, Software Design & Implementation, Operating Systems, Information & the Internet, Design & Analysis of Algorithms

## Projects

Please visit my website at the jasondong.com for more in-depth and updated descriptions of my past and ongoing work.

I have experience working in an agile scrum environment, as part of an engineering group interacting with clients, and on solo software and hardware projects.

## ACTIVITIES

 $\bf Design \ @ \ Duke$  - Treasurer and co-founder

Fall 2020 - Present

**Duke Poker Club** 

Fall 2019 - Present

**Asian Students Association** - Part of a family with other Duke students, responsible for organizing events and outings.

Fall 2018 - Present

Running Club

Fall 2018 - Present